Finding Aid for Year 2000 Information Campaign (University of Michigan) website, 1997-2000
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Year 2000 Information Campaign (University of Michigan) website 1997-2000
University of Michigan. Year 2000 Information Campaign.
95 digital documents (3.71 MB)
9914 Aa 2
The Year 2000 Information Campaign was formed as part of the University’s concern and overall plan to insure that the information systems used on campus would not be affected by the "Millennium Bug"-- the possiblility thtat computer systems would not properly process date values with the turnof the century. Records include the Year 2000 Information Campaign website as of Nov. 2000. The website includes information created to assist university units in understanding the year 2000 problem and a methodology for the assessment of information systems. The website includes memoranda from executive officers, quarterly reports, a white paper, and a series of announcements under the title "Bug Bytes."
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The website files were first captured via File Transfer Protocol by the Bentley Historical Library in October 2000. Donor No. 7873, Inofromatino Technology Division.
No additonal records are expected.
The record group is open for research.
Access to the archived website is provided on CD-ROM. The main access points to the collection are the Bentley Library home page and the catalog record stored in the MIRLYN system. At the time of the October 2000 capture, the following software version numbers were prevalent: Internet Explorer 4.0/5.0, Netscape Navigator 4.0, Adobe Acrobat 4.0, Adobe Acrobat Reader 4.0, Excel Microsoft Office 2000, and PowerPoint Microsoft Office 2000. The HTML files were coded in HTML 3.2
The Year 2000 Information Campaign was formed as part of the university's concern and overall plan to insure that the information systems used on campus would not be effected by the "Millennium Bug." The Millennium Bug or the "Year 2000 Problem" (Y2K) referred to administrative systems designed circa 1970s. Disk storage space was considered expensive at this time and was a factor in the design of systems. As a way to decrease the amount of storage space used, programmers limited the date field to a two digit field instead of a four digit field. For example, the date 1966, would be expressed as 66. Y2K concerns centered on what would happen on January 1, 2000 when the two digit date 00 would be interpreted in non-compliant systems as 1900 rather than 2000. The Year 2000 concern focused in particular on systems that relied on the date field for calculations and other business transactions. The university itself depended on numerous computer based systems for it's daily operations. These systems ranged from systems designed for building security, heating and cooling, and elevator maintenance to systems designed for financial transactions.
In October 1997 the Regents requested that the university identify and measure the potential impact of the Year 2000 problem. Executive Officers Nancy Cantor, Robert Kasdin, and Gilbert Omenn, charged Jose Marie-Griffiths (University Chief Information Officer and Executive Director), Robert Moenart (Controller), Laura Patterson (M-Pathways Project Director), and Glenna Schweitzer, (Director of Budget Administration) to this task.
The university undertook a comprehensive managed approach to identifying systems, software, and vendors that may not be Year 2000 complaint. The university either replaced or upgraded those systems that were judged likely to fail in the Year 2000. In addition to insuring the operational integrity of the systems, the university also formed a Year 2000 Information Campaign as an effort to raise the awareness of the problem on campus and to communicate the progress the university made towards the Year 2000 Problem. Gloria Thiele acted as the Project Coordinator for the Year 2000 Information Campaign under the direction of Jose Marie-Griffiths.
The Year 2000 Information Campaign WEBSITE series, first captured via File Transfer Protocol in October 2000 includes the entire contents of the Year 2000 Information Campaign website. The WEBSITE series includes 71 HTML files, 8 PowerPoint files, 11 Microsoft Word files, and 5 GIF files. The website target audience was University of Michigan units. The website includes information to assist units in understanding what the Year 2000 problem consisted of and provided individual units with a methodology for the assessment of their information systems. The series consists of four subseries: University of Michigan Year 2000 Activities, University of Michigan Unit Action, University of Michigan Year 2000 Working Groups, and Year 2000 Announcements. As noted in the access requirements section, the origin directory structure of the website was maintained. When accessing a subseries however, note that the original structure was essentially flat.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Information Technology Division.; Year 2000 date conversion (computer systems)
Genre Terms:
CD--ROMs
- Website 2000
  - University of Michigan Year 2000 Activities (Box 1)
    The University of Michigan Year 2000 Activities subseries is comprised of background materials specific to the University Year 2000 efforts and plans. The subseries contains three memoranda from the Executive Officers (HTML version), a calendar of activities, Quarterly Reports from the Year 2000 Project Committee and the Year 2000 Impact Committee, and a white paper on the requirements and progress of activities at the university written by Gloria Thiele, Year 2000 Project Coordinator.
    - Executive Office Memoranda, 1997-1999
    - Calendar of Activities, 1998-2000
    - Year 2000 Issues and Concerns
    - Year 2000 Project Committee Quarterly Report, 1999
    - Year 2000 Impact Committee Quarterly Reports, April 1998- February 1999
    - Communications and Event Management Process Report and Recommendations, September 7, 1999
  - University of Michigan Unit Action
    The University of Michigan Unit Action subseries includes instructions, forms, and guidelines to aid university units in assessing their information systems. This subseries includes documentation that reflects how the Year 2000 Campaign worked to raise the awareness of the Y2K Bug and to provide guidance to units in the evaluation of their systems.
    - Instructions and Forms
    - Guidelines for Contingency Planning
    - Unit Assessment Tools
    - PowerPoint Presentations
    - Suggested Compliance Project Methodology.
  - University of Michigan Year 2000 Working Groups
    The University of Michigan Year 2000 Working Groups subseries includes the directories of those persons involved in the Y2K effort.
    - Impact Committee Directory
    - Y2K Working Group Directory
  - University of Michigan Year 2000 Announcements
    The Year 2000 Announcements subseries consists of the announcements written by the Year 2000 Campaign for the university units. The announcements, titled "Bug Bytes," date from July, 1998 to December 15, 1999.
    - Bug-Bytes July 1, 1998- December 15, 1999
      - July 1, 1998
      - July 15, 1998
      - July 31, 1998
      - August 12, 1998
      - September 25, 1998
      - October 14, 1998
      - December 2, 1998
      - February 11, 1999
      - March 25, 1999
      - April 30, 1999
      - June 4, 1999
      - July 19, 1999
      - August 13, 1999
      - November 8, 1999
      - November 10, 1999
      - December 15, 1999